《哥谭》前情提要
Previously on Gotham...
听着  我还有事得处理
Listen. There are things I need to do.
你不走我也不走
If you stay, I stay.
我叫维克多・萨斯
My name is Victor Zsasz.
我来这里是为了找吉姆・戈登
I'm here for Jim Gordon.
所有人都出去
Everybody out.
哥谭市不会有一个警察敢站出来帮你
There's not a single cop in the city who will help you.
我是不会帮你的
I won't help you.
我是不会离开的
I'm not leaving.
你不用跟我一起来的
You don't have to join me.
反正我横竖都是死
I figure I'm doomed anyhow.
倒不如跟好人搏一把
I might as well join the good guys.
我要找的不是美女
I ain't looking for no girl.
而是武器
I'm looking for a weapon.
打扰
Excuse me.
你想为这个小瘪三而挑起战争吗
You want to start a war over this punk?
那小家伙会逗我开心
The little guy amuses me.
何必为点小事而搅起战火呢
Why go to war over trifles?
你就留着他吧
We'll let you have him.
算是送你的礼物
Our gift to you.
本字幕由 YYeTs 人人影视 原创翻译
[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]再加工制作
本人由衷感谢原译作者的无私奉献  并保留所有译作者的信息
如需其它剧集字幕  请登陆新浪微博（http://weibo.com/MJZM100）
或发邮件索取 lj20090303@163.com
天啊  天啊
Oh, God, oh, God.
翻译：灰灰是菇凉   艾瑞卡   Reginamoon   木浅薰
翻译：Silence   DustD   charcie   哥谭直属   草草
时间轴：Kallen   凭陵新月   讷讷       后期：宝宝
特效：宝宝          校对&总监：草草
一大早就这么倒霉
Hell of a way to start the day.
我刚洗过领带
I mean, I just cleaned this.
哈维
Harvey.
警员巡逻发现了尸体
Uniforms found the body.
没有钱包  身份证  表也没了
No wallet, no ID, no watch.
他被人暴打过
He got beaten up pretty good.
我猜致命伤是他颈侧的
I'm guessing the cause of death is that gigantic gash
那道巨大裂口
in the side of his neck.
是吗  他身上黑乎乎的是什么
You think? What's all the black on him?
墨水  涂料
Ink? Paint?
早  爱德
Good morning, Ed.
早  警探
Detective.
根据凝血程度判断
Going by overall coagulation,
我认为死亡时间是在午夜时分  但是
I'd say time of death is midnight. But...
他几小时前才被抛尸于此
He's only been here for a couple hours.
老鼠才刚开始啃他的耳朵
Rats have just started on his ears.
狡猾的小东西
Sneaky little buggers.
那就不是抢劫杀人  打劫的不会移尸
So, not a mugging. Muggers don't move the body.
他的指关节有擦伤
Abrasions on his knuckles...
看来奋力抵抗了
Put up a fight.
瞧瞧他的吊带裤
Yeah. Look at the suspenders.
应该是金融界的
I'm guessing he's some kind of finance guy.
也许有人绑了他索要赎金  结果事态恶化
Maybe it was an abduction ransom thing gone wrong.
他反抗  就被撕票了
He resists, ka-chunk!
要跟发现尸体的巡警谈谈吗
Do you want to talk to the uniforms that found the body?
你去吧
Uh, you do it.
我们还得在附近做排查
We should canvass the area, though;
这里有很多流浪汉出没
a lot of homeless around here.
我找些警员来办
I'll get some unis on it.
我自己去
I'll handle it myself.
喂  乔
Hey, Joe!
去别的地方抽烟
Go smoke somewhere else, huh?
别这样  吉姆  小警员就是用来使唤的
Come on, Jim, that's what we got uniforms for.
让他们来吧
Let them do it.
我宁可自己来
And I'd rather handle it myself.
两位警探
Detectives...
我是不是该把每根手指的指纹都验一遍
I'm guessing I should run all the prints?
对  爱德  都验一遍
Yeah, Ed, run the prints.
这根也要吗
This one, too?
对  爱德  这根也要
Yeah, Ed, that one, too.
连游艇都算不上
It wasn't even a proper yacht.
就是个小破船
No, it's more like a dinghy.
有事吗
Can I help you?
胸针真好看
What a lovely brooch.
谢谢
Thank you.
可以给我吗
May I have it?
我有个朋友一定会喜欢的
I have a friend who would love that.
你说什么
Excuse me?
抱歉
I'm sorry.
可以给我吗  拜托了
May I please have it?
你太客气了
You shouldn't have.
我想表示诚意
I wanted to make a gesture.
希望我们日后
I hope, in time,
能成为朋友
we can be friends.
朋友
Friends?
也是
Sure.
有何不可  过去的都过去了
Why not? What's done is done.
我很高兴你能这么想
I'm so glad you feel that way.
马罗尼阁下要我们理一理协议
Don Maroni wants us to clarify terms.
生意还是跟以往一样
Well, it's business as usual.
毒品归马罗尼卖  他还有工会
Maroni still has his drugs, his unions.
进口关税由他出
He pays tariff for the ports.
如果他需要警察或是市长的帮助
If he needs favors from the cops or the mayor,
法尔科内阁下也会考虑的
Don Falcone will consider it.
当然了  阿卡姆项目还是大家一起做
And, of course, the families still share Arkham.
两边都不需要流血牺牲
And there is to be no blood spilled on either side.
一点都不会
Not a drop.
也许有一点
Maybe just a drop.
瞧瞧你啊
Look at you.
蒂莫西
Timothy,
你知道这家伙以前就做你的工作吗
do you know this fellow used to have your job?
替我打伞  还觉得特荣耀呢
Carried my umbrella and thought it an honor.
现在瞧瞧他
Now look at him.
已经能跟我坐一张桌子了
Has a seat at the table.
世事无常啊
Things change, eh?
我很幸运
I've been blessed.
或许我该拆礼物了
Perhaps I should open your gift.
老天
My goodness.
真漂亮
That is beautiful.
这下我都不好意思了
Now I feel awful.
-我都没给你买什么  -不用
- I didn't get you anything. - No.
谢谢你
Thank you.
滋味儿不错
Sweet.
没这个必要吧
That was uncalled for.
我把你纳入家门
I brought you into my family
视你如己出
and I treated you like a son!
但你却背叛了我
And you betrayed me.
我也因此遭过罪了
For which I suffered.
远远不够
Not enough.
我要让哪个蠢货去死
When I order some fool killed,
那人就得死
I expect him to stay that way.
你的老大  法尔科内阁下
Your boss, Don Falcone,
明确表示...
expressly said...
没错没错  他想要和平
Yeah, yeah, yeah, he wants peace.
他是你现在还活着的唯一原因
He's the only reason why your ass is still alive.
我要是你
And if I were you,
就会祈祷他长命百岁
I would pray for his good health.
我会的
Oh, I do.
I do.
很好
Good.
要记住
'Cause remember...
世事无常
...things change.
代我向你的阁下问好
Convey my respects to your Don.
你也是
Likewise.
和平
Peace...
朋友
friend.
哥谭
第一季  第八集
来吧  布鲁斯少爷
Come now, Master Bruce.
该来的总要来
Had to happen sooner or later.
真有这必要吗
Is this really necessary?
在家自学一样有效
Homeschooling is just as effective.
我可以给你看数据
I can show you the data.
你需要跟同龄的孩子待在一起
You need to be around children your own age.
为什么
Why?
因为你需要
'Cause you do.
你知道我不喜欢这样的回答
You know I despise that sort of answer.
你不想你的同学吗
Don't you miss your mates?
不怎么想
Not really.
我一直觉得他们有点幼稚
I've always found them kind of childish.
他们本不就该幼稚吗
Well, that's what they're meant to be, aren't they?
这个年纪就这样
That's what they do.
你难道不想
Don't you want to be
像个正常孩子一样吗
like a normal kid?
我不确定
I'm not sure.
讲讲什么算"正常"  再说服我做个正常孩子
Define "normal" and make a good case for it.
你必须得去上学
You're going to bloody school.
去吧
Now start walking.
祝你好运  孩子
Good luck, lad.
节哀顺变  女士
Very sorry for your loss, ma'am.
你能想到任何会想伤害你儿子科曼的人吗
Can you think of anyone who would want to hurt your son Coleman?
没有
No, sir.
没有人
Nobody.
他是个好孩子
He was a good boy.
是的  夫人  看得出来
Yes, ma'am, I can see that.
无犯罪记录  老实的年轻人
No arrests. An honest young man.
他是做什么的
What did he do for a living?
他在咖啡店上班
Uh, he worked in a coffee shop.
我们找到他时  他穿着西装
When we found him, he was in a suit.
吊带裤
Suspenders.
他想进入金融业
He was looking for a job in finance.
他很有志气
He was very ambitious.
我们家第一个大学生
First in our family to go to college.
谁会下此毒手  这是为什么
Who would do this, sir? Why?
我们会尽力查明真相  女士
We'll do our best to find out, ma'am.
戈登与死者母亲谈完话了
Gordon's finishing up with the mother.
目前为止  断指上查不到什么
So far, nothing off the severed thumb
市内又没有哪家急诊室收治过没有拇指的人
and none of the city's ERs have seen any thumbless guys.
你觉得他是去黑市了吗
You think he went black market?
正准备去查
That's next on my list.
戈登怎样了
How's Gordon?
很生气
Angry.
假如这里的每个警察都抛弃了你  你会怎么想
How would you feel if every cop in the building ran out on you?
如今人人都把他视作为瘟疫
And now they all treat him like he's got the plague,
因为看见他  他们就会想起自己多么懦夫
'cause seeing him reminds them of what cowards they all are.
抱歉  警监  我...
I'm sorry, Cap, I...
我不是在说你
I didn't mean you.
不
Nope.
你说的没错
You're right.
但他必须翻过这一页
But he's gotta get over that.
他不能孤军奋战
Can't do this job alone.
幸好他还有你
Lucky he's got you.
是啊
Yeah.
太漂亮了
So beautiful.
我一看到这个
As soon as I saw it,
就想到了你
I thought of you.
我的好儿子啊
Such a good son.
给我戴上  给我戴上
Put it on, put it on.
发生什么了
Wh-What happened?
谁干的
Who did this?
没谁
N-Nobody.
就是个抓伤...只是...
It's just a scratch. It's...
当你母亲是傻子吗
Is your mother a fool?
不对  有人欺负我儿子
No. Someone is being mean to my boy.
这行很凶险
It's a tough business.
如今餐饮业都这么凶险了吗
The restaurant business is so tough these days?
为什么会这样
Why is that?
我的成功引起了其他人的嫉妒
My success makes other people envious.
那就向老板告这些人的状啊
So tell the boss on these people.
这人不怕老板
This person isn't scared of the boss.
没有应有的敬畏
Not like they should be.
我不明白为什么
I don't know why.
我明白
I know.
我上学的时候
When I was in school,
玛格达・汉密法布对我特别坏
Magda Himmelfarb was so mean to me
而老师也听之任之
and teacher did nothing.
为什么
Why?
因为我当时是个很好的舞者
Because such a good dancer I was.
而玛格达
And Magda,
留着一头秀发
with her nice hair
长着一对大胸
and her big bosoms,
就是个人尽可夫的婊子
a carthorse.
我是想问...
I meant...
为什么老师听之任之呢
why did the teacher do nothing?
你觉得呢
Why you think?
他们说老师给她"单独授课"
"Private lessons," they said.
我制止了他们
I put stop to that.
你告发了他们吗
You told on them?
不是的
Oh, no.
我向秘密警察揭发了玛格达的父亲
I denounced Magda's father to secret police.
三周了
Three weeks
他一直对我设的陷阱不屑一顾
he's been turning up his nose at my traps,
而今天呢  我放了软质乳酪
and now, now, today, a smidge of Camembert
老鼠先生就抵挡不住诱惑了
and Mr. Rat, he cannot resist.
抵挡不住  不是吗
No. Oh, can you?
是不是啊  我贪婪的小宝贝
Can you, my little greedy baby?
我发现你的秘密了
I found out your secret!
没错
Yes.
人人都有秘密
Everybody has a secret.
吗啡
Morphine!
这是在医学院学来的吗
They teach you that in med school?
布洛克
Bullock.
那不是肯尼・萨菲尔德吗
Is that Kenny Suffield?
抢劫犯一个
Smash and grab guy.
还经常去骚扰女人
Also a real hound with the ladies.
谁开的枪
Who shot him?
我不问问题
I don't ask.
我和我搭档正在走访你们这些
Well, me and my partner doing all the rounds
非法外科医生
of you black market sawbones.
我们找的人应该是今早来的
Guy we're looking for would've come in early this morning
-还缺一个拇指  -抱歉
- missing a thumb. - Sorry.
如果你知道就会告诉我们  对吧  医生
You'd tell us if you knew, wouldn't you, Doc?
这是我们说好的  对吧
I mean, that's the deal, right?
你提供消息  我们就让你继续经营
You give us info and we let you keep operating?
这是句双关哦  经营和手术
That's a pun. Operating.
布洛克  黑色墨迹
Bullock, black ink,
和死者身上的一样
just like on the victim.
医生啊
Oh, Doc.
好吧
Fine.
他今天凌晨3点左右来的
He came in about 3:00 this morning.
没留名字
Didn't give a name,
但这是他口袋里掉出来的
but this dropped out of his pocket.
西恩尼斯投资
Sionis Investments.
他长什么样
What'd he look like?
20多岁
Mid-20s.
穿西装  吊带裤
Suit, suspenders.
和死者一样
Just like our dead guy.
抱歉  医生
Sorry, Doc.
我是戈登  立刻派救护车和警车
This is Gordon. I need an ambulance
到威尔顿1856号
and a black and white at 1856 Wilton.
等等
Wait!
等一下
Just... wait a second.
我要见阿尔瓦雷斯  行吗
Just get me Alvarez, will you?
布洛克  布洛克  搞什么啊
Bullock, Bullock, what the hell, man?
我和这人有协议的
I got a deal with that guy.
-协议失效了  -但我什么都告诉你了
- Deal's off. - But I told you everything.
在我们发现你说谎之后
Yeah, after we caught you in a lie.
他总会撒个谎
He always lies.
你多逼问几句就行了
You just squeeze him.
-你这是在坑我们大家  -是吗
- You're screwing the rest of us. - Oh, yeah?
感觉如何啊  喜欢吗
How's that feel? You like it?
够了  够了
Hey, enough, enough!
我理解  我理解  行吗
I get it, I get it, huh?
这些混蛋关键时刻都没帮你
None of these sons of bitches had your back when it mattered,
但我呢
but where was I?
我帮了你  记得吗
I was there, remember?
法尔科内  市长  你逞英雄的时候
Falcone, the mayor, blaze of glory?
看在我的分上  客气点
Be nice for my sake.
-我很客气了  -你还没得到教训吗
- I am being nice. - Haven't you learned your lesson?
我们没死是因为法尔科内允许我们活
We're only alive because Falcone let us live.
你得遵守规则才能混下去  吉姆
You got to go along to get along, Jim.
-我不要  -你觉得把那个
- No, I don't. - You think locking up
混蛋医生抓起来  就能改变什么吗
Doc scumbag there is gonna make a difference?
我是你这边的  我向你证明了这点
I'm on your side. I proved that.
没错  你是证明了
Yeah, you did.
所以我求你  拜托了
So I'm asking you, please,
放了那个医生吧  明天
let the doc out and tomorrow,
我就和你一起去调查这个西恩尼斯投资
you and I will go check out this Sionis Investments together.
行吗  搭档
All right, partner?
抱歉  哈维
Sorry, Harv.
-这可不好  哈维  -阿尔瓦雷斯
- This ain't right, Harvey. - Alvarez,
给我闭嘴
put a zipper on it!
吉姆
Jim.
芭芭拉  你这是...
Barbara, what are you...
我听到有人进来了  你又不开灯...
I heard someone come in, and you didn't turn on the light...
那你就拿我的备用枪
So you got out my spare?
你回来晚了
You were late!
我害怕了
I got nervous.
天呐
God.
喝着酒就不该碰武器
Not the best idea to be handling a firearm when you've been drinking.
对不起
I'm sorry.
我知道你受了折磨
Look, you've been through a lot.
那都过去了
It's over now.
我很害怕  吉姆
I am scared, Jim.
不管我去哪里  我都能
Everywhere I go, I can...
我都能感觉到那怪物萨斯
I can feel that monster, Zsasz,
-跟踪我  我...  -他不是怪物
- stalking me, and I... - He's not a monster.
他只是个人
He's just a man.
我不会让任何人伤害你的
I won't let anyone hurt you.
这你要怎么保证
How can you promise me that?
告诉我不会有事的
Tell me it'll be okay.
告诉我真的没有什么怪物
Tell me there really aren't any monsters.
不行的话
Just...
骗骗我也好
lie if you have to.
真的没有怪物
There aren't any monsters.
我们什么时候能离开这里
When are we gonna get out of here?
这就要看你了
That's up to you.
早上好
Morning.
我以为你还没起床
I didn't think you were up.
昨晚我只是精神紧张
Look, last night was just nerves...
而且喝了太多酒
and way too much to drink.
我说过我想分担你一半的包袱  我如愿了
I said I wanted half your life, and I've got it.
把枪留下吧
Leave the gun.
真希望事情不是这样
I wish it wasn't like this.
你真这么想吗
Do you really?
别理我  我只是太累了
Ignore me. I'm just tired.
去吧
Go.
去抓坏蛋
Catch some bad guys.
好
Okay.
爱德华・尼格玛鉴证报告
Forensic examination by Edward Nygma,
早8点42分于哥谭市警局停尸房
8:42 A.M., GCPD morgue.
室温大约19摄氏度
The room is approximately 19 degrees Celsius.
早前我吃了半个蔓越橘松糕
I ate half a cranberry muffin earlier,
晚点再吃另一半
saving the rest for later.
一个死人  一艘游轮
What do a dead man, a cruise ship
和鸸鹋有何关联
and emu have in common?
没错  毫无关联
Correct, nothing.
越来越有趣了
Ever more curious.
他什么
He what?!
尼格玛  我和你说了多少次
Nygma, how many times have I told you
不要进这里来
to stay the hell out of here?
-但是我有发现...  -你再这样做
- But I discovered something. - You'll discover
我就把你扔到街上
your butt in the street if you keep doing this.
出去
Out.
这是你的损失
Your loss.
你个粗心又无知的人
You sloppy ignoramus.
布鲁斯  你好
Hi, Bruce.
小布  你好吗
Brucey, how you doing?
汤米
Tommy, hey.
我很好  你呢
I'm well, how are you?
挺好的
You know, chilling.
你爸妈被杀了  是吗
So, uh, your mom and dad got killed, huh?
-是  -你目睹了整个过程吗
- Yes. - You see the whole thing?
血溅当场吗
The blood and everything?
我不想说这件事
I'd rather not talk about that.
我只是感兴趣而已
I was just interested.
我从未见过真正的尸体
I've never seen a real dead body.
露肠子了吗
Was there guts?
我要去上课了
I'll be going to class now.
原谅我  院长  我有罪
Forgive me, Mother, for I have sinned.
真逗
Funny.
在这儿见面感觉很怪
It feels weird, meeting here.
你不会希望被人看见我们在一起的
You don't want anyone to see us together.
法尔科内到处都有耳目
Falcone has his eyes everywhere.
进展得怎么样了
So, where are we?
我为他做饭
I cook for him,
给他唱歌
I sing to him,
我们一起散步
we go on walks.
我不知道我是他的女佣  他的情人
I don't know whether I'm his maid, his lover
还是他妈妈
or his mother.
或是三者皆有
Or all three.
他在乎你
He cares about you.
对
Yeah.
你进过他的私人办公室吗
Have you been inside his private office?
进过
Yeah.
好几次
A few times.
在书桌右手边最下面的抽屉里有本账簿
Inside the right bottom desk drawer is a ledger.
拷贝下最后两页
Copy the last two pages.
抽屉是锁着的  你需要钥匙
It'll be locked; you will need a key
从他钥匙链上拿
off of his key ring.
我怎么拿得到
How do I get that?
你身后有个小瓶子
Behind you is a vial.
让他喝下
Give it to him.
他会睡死两个小时
He'll sleep like the dead for two hours.
这个不会害死他吧
It won't kill him, will it?
莉莎
Liza,
你不会对那老头产生感情了吧
you haven't caught feelings for the old man, have you?
完全没有
Not at all.
那东西不会害死他
No, it won't kill him.
现在杀了他只会制造混乱
Killing him now would only create chaos.
我需要吸取他的力量
I need to siphon his strength.
等时机一到
So when the time is right,
推翻他的统治
taking over his organization
就会如同戴手套一样轻松
will be like slipping on a glove.
如果他的哪个手下
What if one of his men
撞见我乱翻呢
catches me snooping?
那你多半死定了
Then you're probably dead.
你先走
You leave first.
好好好
Right, right, right.
我这里压力很大
I'm under a lot of pressure.
即刻成功
准备上战场
我感觉咱们来对地方了
Something tells me we came to the right place.
可不是
You think?
西恩尼斯先生现在可以见你们了
Mr. Sionis will see you now.
理查德・西恩尼斯
Richard Sionis.
詹姆斯・戈登
James Gordon.
这是我搭档  哈维・布洛克
This is my partner, Harvey Bullock.
有什么能帮上忙的吗  警探
How can I help you detectives?
我时间不多
I don't have much time.
你认识这个人吗
You know this man?
科曼・劳森
Coleman Lawson?
他或许来面试过工作
He might have interviewed for a job.
抱歉  不认识
Sorry, no.
你员工昨天有没来上班的吗
Any of your employees miss work yesterday?
有人今天来上班时右手受伤吗
Any of them show up today with an injured right hand?
我不负责点名  警探
I don't take roll call, Detective.
我们能搜查下吗
You mind if we check?
或许你能告诉我这是怎么回事
Perhaps you can tell me what this is about?
科曼・劳森两天前被杀了
Coleman Lawson was killed two night ago.
凶手的口袋里有你们公司的名片
The man who did it had your firm's card in his pocket.
他能拿到名片的地方可多了
Well, there's a thousand ways he could've gotten that.
这些武士玩意是怎么回事
What's with all the warrior baloney?
它们能激励我
It inspires me.
高级金融是个艰难的行当
High finance is tough business.
想要成功  就必须变成武士
In order to succeed, you have to be a warrior.
不  不需要
No, you don't.
当好生意人就可以了
You have to be a good businessman.
武士是打仗的
Warriors fight wars.
完全不同
It's different.
你是把自己想象成杀手了吗
So you fancy yourself a killer?
你杀过人吗  西恩尼斯先生
Have you killed people, Mr. Sionis?
没动过真格的
Only metaphorically.
所以这些只是在玩过家家吗
So all this is just juvenile play acting.
没错
Exactly.
看来你是真上过战场
Thus speaks a man who's seen actual combat.
你真杀过人  对吧
You've killed people for real, haven't you?
真正的杀手一眼就能看出
True killers are easy to spot.
是的  没错
Yes, they are.
那些面具是干吗的
Why all the masks?
心理医生会说你想隐藏什么
A shrink would say you're hiding something.
正相反
To the contrary.
面具虽隐藏了面孔
A mask hides the face,
但却释放了灵魂
but frees the soul.
面具道出真相
A mask speaks the truth.
真深奥
Deep.
为什么你手下那么多员工都挂彩了
How come so many of your employees have scars and injuries?
我们触身式橄榄球打得很激烈
Our touch football games get very rough.
你在撒谎  西恩尼斯先生
You're a liar, Mr. Sionis.
好大的火气
Such fire.
你一定很想念战场吧
You must miss the battlefield desperately.
我猜杀人会上瘾呢
I imagine killing gets quite addictive.
你杀了科曼・劳森  是不是
You murdered Coleman Lawson, didn't you?
证据呢
Prove it.
我们会找到的
We will.
我倒想唱红脸
I'd give you a good cop routine,
可惜我不会
but it's not in my tool kit.
哥谭市警局
GCPD.
慢慢转过身来
Turn around slowly.
举起双手
Let me see those hands!
不许动
Don't move!
你应该等我的
You should've waited for me.
好啊  小布
Hey, Brucey.
我叫布鲁斯
It's Bruce.
不是什么小布
No "y."
你没爸没妈  我愿怎么叫你就怎么叫
No parents, either, so I can call you what I like.
麻烦你  别挡我的道
Please, get out of my way.
还挺嚣张啊
Snobby little jerk, isn't he?
你个孤儿
For an orphan.
你很过分
You're being very unkind.
我不知道你为什么这样
I don't understand why.
天啊  你可真怪
Boy, you're a weirdo.
你妈妈一定...
Your mother must...
不许提我妈妈
Don't talk about my mother.
是吗
Oh, really?
是蒂莫西吗
Oh, is that Timothy?
我们在菲什・穆尼那儿见过面
We met at Fish Mooney's, hmm?
我以前做你的工作
I'm the fellow who used to have your job.
我想问你几个问题
I was hoping to ask you a few questions.
我什么都不知道
I don't know any...
有你说话的时间
They'll be time for that.
首先
First things first.
多数凶手会在犯罪现场留下手印  而你却不
Most killers leave their prints at the crime scene, but not you, no.
你把整个大拇指都留在了死者嘴里
You left your whole thumb in the dead guy's mouth.
挺有风格的  我喜欢你  小子
You got style! I like you, kid.
这是你最后的机会
This is your last chance.
一旦我们走出那扇门
Once we walk out that door...
你就完蛋了
It's over.
我是自卫
It was self-defense.
那当然了
Of course it was.
我不就是这么说的吗  吉姆
Wasn't that what I said, Jim?
我不就说有可能是自卫吗
Didn't I say it was probably self-defense?
交待
Talk.
戈登在做剩下的笔录
Gordon's getting the rest of his statement.
他说那是招聘的一个步骤
Apparently it was part of the hiring process.
西恩尼斯让最后三位候选人打架定胜负
Sionis told the top three candidates to fight it out.
本来不该打得你死我活  但...
They weren't supposed to fight to the death, but...
真是难以置信
This is unbelievable.
他们都签了保密协议
They all signed confidentiality agreements,
发生了什么  他们都会是从犯
so they're accomplices to whatever happens.
知道他们在哪里斗殴吗
Do we know where the fight was held?
老办公楼
Some old office building.
窗户都用木板封住了
The windows were boarded up.
他被带进去时双眼是蒙住的
And he was taken there blindfolded.
什么事  爱德
Yes, Ed?
打印机碳粉
Printer toner.
你知道他在说什么吗
Do you know what he's talking about?
法医报告说是黑墨
The medical examiner's report said it was black ink.
但我做了检查  是打印机碳粉
But I did my own examination, and it was printer toner.
而且  我在他肩膀上找到了订书针
Also, I pulled staples from his shoulders.
还在肋骨间找到了石墨碎片
And found graphite chips between his ribs.
这人是在办公室被杀的
Your man was killed in an office.
这个我们已经知道了  爱德  谢了
Yeah, we're kind of past that, Ed, but thanks.
-还有什么发现吗  -有
- Is there something else? - Yes.
这让我想起一年前的一个案子
It made me think of a case from a year ago.
年轻人  穿西装
Young man, business suit,
被人用索引卡塞进喉咙  划破了食管
esophagus lacerated from index card shoved down his throat.
于是  我深入调查了一番
So, I did some digging...
还有多少人是被用办公用品杀死的
How many other bodies were killed with office supplies?
过去三年里  共有四个
Four... in the last three years.
让他签认罪书  赶紧
Get that man to sign a confession. Now.
好像有麻烦了
I think we have a problem.
我跟戈登警探解释过了
I explained to Detective Gordon,
作为亚当斯先生的法律顾问
as counsel to Mr. Adams
我建议他保持沉默
I'd advised him against speaking further.
他所作的任何供述都将
Also, any statements he has made will be considered
被视为逼供
having been made under duress.
西恩尼斯给了他多少钱让他来顶罪
Uh-huh, and how much is Sionis paying him to take the fall?
再见
Good day.
亚当斯给口供签字之前他就来了
He showed up before Adams could sign his statements.
我们得搞清楚西恩尼斯在哪举行殴斗
We got to figure out where Sionis is staging these fights.
我去查他和他公司在哥谭所拥有的大楼
I'll run all the buildings he or his company owns in Gotham.
你能理解这种事吗
This make any sense to you?
不能  不过也不会比山羊杀手和气球人更糟了
No, but how's it any worse than the Goat or the Balloonman?
这种事什么时候变成日常了
When did this become normal for this city?
是什么变了
What changed?
也许什么都没变  也许一直都藏在表面下
Maybe nothing. Maybe it was always just below the surface.
只需一点刺激
Only needed a spark.
比如托马斯和玛莎・韦恩的死
Like Thomas and Martha Wayne being killed?
我可不瞎  戈登
I'm not blind, Gordon.
我知道你还在查这个
I know you're still looking into it.
但是他们的死怎么会引发这些事情
But how could their deaths have caused all this?
他们为什么那么重要
Why were they so important?
我想是因为他们的意义
I think it's what they represented.
他们代表了一个不同的哥谭
A different Gotham.
正派  有希望
Decent, hopeful.
不管是什么  现在都不复存在了
Whatever it was, it's gone now.
萨斯来找你的时候  我该留下的
When Zsasz came for you, I should've stayed.
我让你走的
I told you to go.
那不重要  我该留下的
That doesn't matter. I should've stayed.
去抓住这家伙吧
Now, let's get this guy.
好的
Yeah.
有点迟了  布鲁斯少爷
Tad late, Master Bruce.
-你怎么了  -我很好
- Oi. What happened to you? - I'm perfectly fine!
怎么了
What happened?
有人侮辱我母亲
Someone spoke disrespectfully about my mother.
是嘛
Oh, did they now?
希望你把那混蛋打得满地找牙
Well, I hope you broke their bastard teeth for them.
没有
No.
他比我壮很多  我...
He's much bigger than me, and I...
我不太擅长打架
I'm not very good at fighting.
一点都没伤到他
Didn't hurt him at all.
一点都没
Not at all?
别告诉学校
Don't tell the school.
当然不会
Not bloody likely.
瞧瞧这个
Take a look at this.
西恩尼斯拥有半个哥谭
Sionis owns half of Gotham!
好吧  我们分头查
All right, we'll split up.
重点查被遗弃
Focus on the buildings that are abandoned
或正在施工的建筑
or under construction first.
这王八羔子别想逃掉
This son of a bitch is not getting away!
我就说一点  他看透了你
I'll say one thing-- he has your number.
-你说什么  -西恩尼斯
- What are you talking about? - Sionis.
你也许对科波特下不了杀手  小吉米
You may not have put down Cobblepot, Jimmy boy,
但是你也有心魔
but you got a demon in you.
你可以说自己是士兵
You can call yourself a soldier,
但是对抗法尔科内
but all this fighting Falcone,
对抗其他警察
fighting other cops,
你是喜欢这么做  所以如果你找到
you love it. So, when you find something
任何有可能的线索  联系我
that seems remotely possible, call me.
芭芭拉  一切都好吧
Barbara, everything all right?
很好  我只是
Fine. I just, uh,
我想问问你的情况
I wanted to check in.
回头聊好吗  我现在正在忙
Can we talk later? I'm kind of in the middle of something.
当然
Of course.
我爱...
I love...
老大要喝茶
Boss wants his tea.
快好了
It's almost ready.
哥谭市警局
GCPD!
还有其他人吗
Anybody else here?
答案
That...
是肯定的
would be a yes.
-好了  加奶加糖  -嗯
- All right, cream and sugar. - Yeah.
姑娘家总得购物啊
A girl's got to shop.
这个
This...
是你父亲的手表
is your father's watch.
可别丢了
Don't you lose it now.
汤米・埃利奥特家
Tommy Elliot's house.
别害怕
Don't you be scared.
我不怕
I'm not.
我在想象我要做的事
I'm visualizing what I'm gonna do.
你如果不想这么做也没什么丢人的
'Cause you if you don't want to do this, there's no shame in it.
那会是很丢人的
There would be immense shame in it.
你来干什么
What the hell are you doing here?
我们有未了结的事
We have unfinished business.
听着  如果你想告诉我父母...
Listen, if you think you're gonna tell my parents...
你疯了吗
Are you crazy?!
不许你说我妈妈
Don't talk about my mother!
布鲁斯少爷
Master Bruce!
你已经很好地表明了自己的立场
Point well made, I think.
你没事吧  伙计
You all right, mate?
断骨头了吗
Any broken bones?
他想杀我
He-he tried to kill me!
是啊
That's right.
的确
He did.
他想杀你
He tried to kill you.
下次你再见到他  要记住这一点
Just you remember that next time you see him.
同时也记住
And you remember
我可没拦着他
that I let him try.
去给手指敷敷冰吧
Now, let's get some ice on those knuckles.
晚饭想吃什么
What do you fancy for your dinner?
披萨
Pizza.
Pizza?
选得好  布鲁斯少爷
Superb choice, Master Bruce.
吉姆  你小子哪去了
Jim, where the hell are you?
我没查到东西  给我打电话
My list crapped out. Call me.
尼格玛  戈登没打来电话吧
Nygma, Gordon hasn't called in, has he?
没有  但如果警探下落不明...
No. But if the detective becomes the mystery...
醒醒
Wake up.
戈登警探
Detective Gordon?
醒醒
Wake up!
你们三个人来我公司申请职位
So, three of you applied for a position at my firm.
我解释说
I explained then
你们可以使用这里任何东西做武器
you can use anything here as a weapon
最后活着的人就能得到职位
and the last man standing gets the job.
但是呢
However...
今晚很特别
tonight is special.
看到那个没戴面罩的人了吗
You see the man without the mask?
杀了他的人  就算获胜
Whoever kills him... is the victor.
听我说
Listen to me.
我是警察
I'm a cop.
你们现在还没有违法
So far, none of you have broken any laws.
游戏...
Let the games...
开始
begin.
最后机会  都不许动
One last chance! Nobody move!
我还外加一百万签约奖金
And I'll throw in a million-dollar signing bonus.
该死
Ah, crap.
阿尔瓦雷斯
Alvarez.
帮我查查这些地址
I need help checking these addresses.
戈登可能有麻烦了
Gordon might be in trouble.
忙呢
Busy.
下次你老婆打电话来问你的下落
I'm gonna remember that next time your wife calls,
我会记住你的回答的
asking where you are, you putz.
柯林斯
Collins.
伙计  能帮帮我吗
Listen up, man, can I have some help?
听好了  你们这群混蛋
Now, listen up, you sons of bitches!
你们不喜欢戈登
So, you don't like Gordon!
好啊
Fine.
他的确挺混蛋的
He can be a total asshat.
但他还是个警察
But he is still a cop.
你们没有一个人在他需要的时候站出来帮他
And not one of you, not one, stood up when he needed it.
这种事不能有第二次了
That ain't happening twice.
我需要人帮忙查这些地址
I need help checking these addresses.
马上
Now.
给我几个
Give me a couple.
好吧
Okay.
但你会帮我跟我老婆打掩护吧
But you cover with my wife, right?
嗯
Yeah.
结束了
It's over.
我就知道你是个杀手
I knew you had a killer in you.
那么
So...
你的警察兄弟呢
where are your brother police?
他们抛弃你了吗
Did they abandon you?
我不需要他们
I don't need them.
看来那一百万要归我了
Seems I'll have to give myself the million dollars.
吉姆
Jim?
Jim?!
小心
Jim!
谢谢
Thanks.
不客气
You're welcome.
如果我死去*
*If I die
灵魂也堕落*
*And my soul be lost
那就只能怪我自己*
*Ain't nobody's fault but mine
那就只能*
*Ain't nobody's fault
怪我自己*
*But mine
如果我死去*
*If I die
灵魂也堕落*
*And my soul be lost
那就只能怪我自己*
*Ain't nobody's fault but mine.
你来这儿最好有个好原因
You'd better have a good reason for being here.
拿到我要的了吗
Did you get what I asked for?
我想退出
I want out.
不行
No.
他会发现的
He's gonna find out.
或许不是今天  但很快就会的
Maybe not today, but soon.
这值得吗
Is it worth it?
你很有钱
You are rich.
大家都怕你
People are afraid of you.
这还不够吗
Is that not enough?
不
No.
那不够
It's not.
我小时候就住这附近
I grew up not too far from here.
只有一间卧室  没有热水
One bedroom, cold water.
我跟妈妈相依为命
Just me and my mama.
我睡在帘子后面的一张床上
I used to sleep in a bed behind a curtain.
妈妈招待男人的时候  我就躲在那儿
It's where I would hide when she entertained men.
她被杀时我就躲在那儿
And that's where I was when he killed her.
是法尔科内的手下
One of Falcone's men.
嫌她招待得不好
Didn't like the service.
我躲在那儿
I hid there,
一声没出  直到天亮
silent, until morning.
妈妈的尸体就在两英尺开外
With my mama two feet away from me.
那晚  我立誓
That night, I made a promise.
报仇雪恨
To get revenge.
再也不要软弱无力
To never again be powerless.
再也不许任何男人
To never let any man,
任何男人  在我之上
any man, be over me.
我要实现那个小女孩的誓言
This is about keeping that promise to that little girl.
那这是做什么的
So, what's this about?
这是一根线
This is a thread.
我一拉线  法尔科内就会倒台
I pull this and Falcone comes undone.
你害怕
You're scared.
但我不会让你出事的
But I won't let anything happen to you,
这我保证
and that's a promise.
你说
I want you to say--
"我相信你  妈妈"
"I believe you, Mama."
我相信你  妈妈
I believe you, Mama.
好姑娘
That's my girl.
你瞧  我当初做你的工作时
The thing is, when I had your job,
如果有人问我  "穆尼女士的秘密是什么"
had someone asked me, "What is Miss Mooney's secret?"
我会说出来的
I could've answered.
蒂莫西
Timothy...
我觉得你有所隐瞒啊
I think you're holding back on me.
好吧
Okay, I...
我可能听到她跟布奇说话了
I might've heard her with Butch.
说什么  说谁
Talking about what? Whom?
法尔科内
Fal... Falcone.
她说
She said, "Our...
"我们在法尔科内身边的朋友"
our friend with Falcone."
就是这样
That's it.
她说话声很低  求你了
She was whispering. Please.
她在法尔科内身边安插了人
She has someone close to Falcone.
当然了
Of course.
谢谢
Thank you.
别让人发现尸体
No one can find the body.
不要
No.
我们还在休战呢
We are at peace after all.
不要啊  求你
No! No, please!
不要
No! No...!
阿尔瓦雷斯和柯林斯在把西恩尼斯手下抓回来了
Alvarez and Collins are bringing in Sionis' minions.
那些混蛋看见你抓走了他们的老板  试图逃跑
Pansies tried to rabbit when they saw you cuffing their boss.
你没事吧
You okay?
艾森说你之前大发感慨
Essen told me you made a speech.
算不上
I wouldn't call it a speech.
还说你说我是混蛋
Said you called me an asshat.
这倒不假
I did call you that.
谢谢
Thank you.
谢谢你挺我
For having my back.
这次  还有之前
Now and before.
以后别那么讨厌了
Just try not to be such a pain in the neck.
让我很不好过
Makes my day harder.
你错了
You know, you were wrong.
你之前的话
What you said earlier.
我不是喜欢打
It's not that I love fighting.
但我也不害怕
But I'm not afraid to, either.
如果我们不为哥谭而战  还有谁会
And if we don't fight for this city, who will?
我不会停手的  哈维
I'm not gonna stop, Harvey.
法尔科内  市长  每个有问题的警察
Falcone, the mayor, every cop I know that's dirty,
我会抓到他们所有人
I'm gonna get them.
你要知道
You should know that.
回家吧  吉姆
Go home, Jim.
你今晚听我们说话了  是吧
You were listening tonight, weren't you?
你要给自己惹麻烦的  老太婆
You gonna get in trouble, old woman.
我听见你跟那女孩说的故事了
Heard you telling that girl stories.
情真意切的谎言很有力量
A lie with a heart of truth is a powerful thing.
走吧  很晚了
Go on, it's late.
吉姆来电
吉姆
是我
Hey, it's me.
我这就回家
I'm coming home soon.
一切都会好起来  我保证
Everything is gonna be better, I promise.
我爱你
I love you.
戈登
Hey, Gordon.
有时间吗
Got a minute?
能等等吗
Can it wait?
我正要走呢
Kind of on my way out of here.
有巡警抓回来个罪犯
Some unis brought in a perp.
自称认识你
Claims to know you.
是吗  什么罪名
Oh, yeah? What's the charge?
擅闯上城区的高档商店
B and E, some fancy store uptown.
干得挺不错的
Pretty professional job.
那孩子都没触动警报
Kid didn't even trip the alarm.
孩子
Kid?
男孩女孩
Boy or girl?
女孩
Girl.
还让我问你最近有没有下过下水道
Said to ask if you been down any sewers lately.
你好啊  警探
Hey, Detective.
想我了吗
Miss me?
我很喜欢
I enjoyed it.
我喜欢伤害他
I enjoyed hurting him.
当然了
Of course you did.
他活该挨揍
He deserved it.
我总是好生气
I'm so angry all the time.
这感觉会消退吗
Will that ever go away?
这...我不知道
That I don't know.
阿尔弗雷德
Alfred...
你能教我打斗吗
...can you teach me how to fight?
当然  布鲁斯少爷
Yes, Master Bruce.
没问题
Yes, I can.
如需其它字幕  请登陆新浪微博[WEB&BD版美剧字幕精编者]
或发邮件 lj20090303@163.com